From
Mohammad TauseefAhsan
A-32/D-19, Indrapuri colony
Rajabazar, Patna-14



Subject: Application for the post of Project Engineer(Electrical)

_	~ :
Dear	Sir,
DCai	JII .

As an experienced **Electrical** E**ngineer** in search of a challenging work environment. I am applying for the vacancy of Electrical Engineer in your esteemed organization. I am very glad to offer myself as a candidate and hope my credentials would match your requirements.

Here with I am furnishing my **CV**with recent photograph for your kind and favorable consideration. I would be very much obliged if you give me an opportunity for a personal interview at your convenient time so that I can prove my mettle and give you more details about me. You may contact me on my **E-mailID- ertauseef@rediffmail.com**, **+917050102327**

All I pray for a fair chance, as I have faith in the Almighty and belief in myself.

Cordially Yours,

Mohammad TauseefAhsan.

CURRICULAM – VITAE

PROFILE:

A professional qualified **Electrical Engineer** having more than. **11** years of experience with knowledge and skill in LV power distribution, FAS & FF etc. of residential and commercial buildings.

Responsibilities have encompassed many aspects of this field; major strength involves, estimation, Execution & achievement of the target of projects, liaison at all levels and having a progressive carrier track record.

PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION:

BSc.Engineering (Electrical) in 2005 from M.U, Bodhgaya.

EXTRA QUALIFICATION:

- 1. Certificate Course in MS Project 2007-CADD Centre, Mumbai.
- 2. Electrical Design of Switchgear Assembly-Advance from Larsen & Tubro, Lucknow.
- 3. Certificate course in Industrial Automation, Prolific Technologies, Noida.
- 4. Certificate course in Auto CAD, New Delhi
- 5. Certificate Course in Auto CAD-CADD Centre, Mumbai.

.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

From, March 2015 to August 2017

Worked as Manager (MEP) with AL SOFI CONTRACTING, Andheri West, and Mumbai for its projects New Corporate office at Andheri.

Job responsibilities:

- Managing all MEP related works of projects from initiation till finalization.
- Coordination with Consultant and architects for obtaining project related approvals for timely start and smooth execution of project.
- Coordination of Fire Alarm, Fire Fighting, CCTV, PAsystem and other Services with concerned agencies

From Feb. 2014 to May. 2014

Worked as a Project Engineer for HBK Engineering Services W.L.L, Qatar (HBK GROUP)

Project details:

B+G+7 Typical Floor Twin Tower Residential Project at Al Saad, Qatar. B+G+2 Typical Floor Office building at 'D' Ring road, Noija, Qatar.

Job responsibilities:

- Studying the specification and contractual obligation
- Preparation of technical specification on the basis of project's requirement
- Preparation of Project schedules for all major project using Microsoft project
- Obtaining drawing and material approvals from Consultant.

- Obtaining government authority approvals for water and Electrical Services from Qatar water & Electricity Authority
- Checking of installation of Bus bars, LV panels, ATS panels and Genenerator
- Attending Factory Acceptance test(FAT) with consultant for Equipments
- Attending technical and progress meeting with client/consultant
- Making requisitions for inspection of works and attending inspection with client and consultant and government authorities for all Electrical works stage wise

From, Jan 2012 to Dec 2013

Worked as Manager (MEP) with **Royal Constructions (Engineers & Developers)** for its projects in Mumbai and Thane.

Job responsibilities:

- Managing all MEP related works of projects from initiation till finalization.
- Providing schedules pertinent to project.
- Identifying resources and requirements, assigning responsibilities and coordinating with project staff directly and indirectly to ensure successful completion of project.
- Tracking project progression using project management tools.
- Preparing Techno-commercial proposals for particular project
- Coordination with Consultant and other authorities for obtaining project related approvals for timely start and smooth execution of project.
- Delivering status reports to top management regularly (monthly/Quarterly).
- Tracing and resolving critical issues to minimize project risk factors.
- Planning and managing projects: [(G+11 Residential Complex at Santa Cruz (E),G+16 Residential cum Commercial complex at Borivalli (W)] and G+4 residential building at Vasai (E).

From October 2009 to Nov 2011.

Worked as a Sr. Technical Engineer with **Al Nasser Group**, Riyadh, Saudi Arabia (Technical and Design Department).

Job responsibilities:

- Managing Technical and design department for optimum performance.
- Specifying lighting fixtures on the basis of project requirements.
- Lighting calculations in Diallux for a particular project (if required).
- Assisting subordinate engineers in preparation of technical submittals.
- Reviewing technical submittals prior to submission to consultant.
- Providing technical clarification to client and consultant.
- Providing technical information to Noortek for new product development.
- Attending technical meeting with Major supplier (e.g. Erco, Arcluce).
- Weekly progress meeting with Divisional Manager.
- Worked as Product Development/Customer support Manager in **Noortek**.

From Jan 2008 to September 2009.

Worked as a Project Engineer for NITCO International (Bukhatir Group-UAE)

Project details:

American & European Medical Centre for Al Dar atYas Island, Abu Dhabi, UAE Material Testing Lab unit) Al Dar Laing O'Rourke at Al Raha beach, Abu Dhabi, UAE.

G+1 Corporate Office for Dubai Dry Dock World, Dubai Classrooms Building for HCT, Abu Dhabi Office Building for ENOC Blending Plant at, Fujairah

Job responsibilities:

- Studying the specification and contractual obligation
- Preparation of technical specification on the basis of client's requirement
- Obtaining drawing and material approvals from ADDC, Abu Dhabi.
- Obtaining drawing and material approvals from ENOC/ADNOC, UAE.
- Preparation of Electrical estimates based on approved drawings
- Design of Electrical Power, Lighting, Fire Alarm and Emergency Lighting as per relevant standards and client requirements
- Fault level calculation for Cable selection and switchgear selection
- Cable schedule and voltage drop calculation
- Sizing of transformer and Capacitor bank
- Sizing of Current Transformers and control transformer
- Sizing of cables
- Quantities take off for all projects
- Allocating jobs to subordinate engineers and site supervisors
- Attending technical and progress meeting with client/consultant
- Inspection of all M& E works prior to the inspection of consultant or client

-Knowledge of DEWA and ADDC Regulation-

From May 2006 to Jan 2008

Worked as Engineer for **EASTERN** International (**Bukhatir Group-UAE**)

Project details:

3B+G+M+4,IT Development office for Emirates International Bank at Al Barsha, Dubai, UAE ADNOC Filling station at Sharjah, UAE

Job responsibilities:

- Studying the specification
- Job distribution to Foreman and lead electrician
- Preparation of material enquiry indent and material indent
- Preparation of shop drawing submittal and material submittals
- Supervision of electrical installation during execution as per approved drawings
- Preparation of weekly progress of electrical installation works
- Attending site coordination meeting

From February 2005 to April 2006

Worked as Electrical Engineer for SHIVAElectricals, Noida Sector-63

Project details:

Power distribution Project (11KV/415V) under supervision of Reliance Energy Limited at SangamVihar, New Delhi

Job responsibilities:

- Supervision of electrical works carried on daily basis
- Installation of HT XLPE AB cable
- Installation of HT XLPE AB cable
- Erection of Steel poles and PSC poles
- Installation of H type pole mounted distribution Transformers substation
- Installation of Three phase 11/0.415kV transformer
- Installation of Single phase 11/0.415kV transformer
- Preparation of Earthing values report
- Preparation of IR values of Cables
- Preparation of Cable schedule with accessories
- Preparation of weekly progress report for electrical installations

Personal appraisals

- Good communication and coordination skill.
- Pride in doing a good job and achieving result.
- Can work under pressure and desire to learn new things.

PERSONAL DETAIL	
Name:	Mohammad TauseefAhsan
Father's Name:	KhwajaQutubuddin
Date of Birth:	16 th February 1980
Sex:	Male
Nationality:	Indian
Passport No:	M 4081073
Visa statusVisit Visa (valid up to Dec 2017)	
Marital Status:	Married
Language Known:	English, Hindi, Urdu, Arabic
Permanent Address:	Durgabari Colony, Gaya, Dist.:- Gaya, Bihar India. Pin: - 823001
Driving License:	Valid Saudi Arabia
Expected Salary:	7000 Dhs

Reference: MD TARIQUE SERAJ MECHANICAL ENGINEER WORKING with BK GULF (CONTACT No: 055016786)

MD MINHAJUDDIN CIVIL ENGINEER WORKING with AL MASOOD BERGUM (CONTACT No: 0506771173)